<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>business on Hack MySQL</title>
    <link>https://hackmysql.com/tags/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in business on Hack MySQL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2022 Daniel Nichter</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 16:31:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hackmysql.com/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is MySQL in the Cloud the End of the DBA?</title>
      <link>https://hackmysql.com/post/book-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 16:31:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackmysql.com/post/book-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No, I don&amp;rsquo;t think so.
But it is does change our profession and have important implications for software engineers using (not managing) MySQL.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NewDB: Fate of an Open Source Database</title>
      <link>https://hackmysql.com/post/newdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 15:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackmysql.com/post/newdb/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve had several discussions with engineers, industry experts, and business people of various titles and functions (from sales to CEO) about the fate of a new open source database. It&amp;rsquo;s not MySQL, and I won&amp;rsquo;t name the real database because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter for the purpose of this post. But to make writing and communication more clear, let&amp;rsquo;s call the database &amp;ldquo;NewDB&amp;rdquo; and the business &amp;ldquo;New Corp.&amp;rdquo;
This blog post is a think piece on how New Corp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Workers Are Good People</title>
      <link>https://hackmysql.com/post/tech-workers-are-good-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 09:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackmysql.com/post/tech-workers-are-good-people/</guid>
      <description>The Other Tech Bubble is a provocative and interesting read. The author clearly has a lot of experience with Silicon Valley and has done their homework. There are many good insights, like &amp;ldquo;They&amp;rsquo;re still asking if it&amp;rsquo;s possible to do something, and not whether they should.&amp;rdquo; But there are two claims and one ambiguity that need to be addressed.
Villains The first claim is:
In 2008, it was Wall Street bankers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideas, Leaders, and Engineers</title>
      <link>https://hackmysql.com/post/ideas-leaders-and-engineers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackmysql.com/post/ideas-leaders-and-engineers/</guid>
      <description>The Senior Engineer&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Helping Others Make Decisions is a good read and good advice. I would summarize the advice as:
&amp;ldquo;Seek first to understand, then to be understood&amp;rdquo; (Dr. Stephen Covey) Lead and guide, don&amp;rsquo;t micromanage Embrace change, which entails embracing other people&amp;rsquo;s thinking and way of doing things In the first dialog, the senior engineer fails those three points.
Av&amp;rsquo;s blog post made me think&amp;hellip;
Good Ideas Let me jump right to the punch line: levels of seniority should not apply to ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
